shiseido.com 2015-06-26

# Privacy

Shiseido Cosmetics has adopted this Privacy Policy in order to inform you of its policies with respect to information collected from this Website. Your use of this Website constitutes your acceptance of this Privacy Policy and your consent to the practices it describes.

**A. Non-Personal Identifiable Information**

As with most websites, when you visit the Shiseido Cosmetics Website certain anonymous information about your visit is automatically logged, which may include information about the type of browser you use, the server name and IP address through which you access the internet, the date and time you access the site, the pages you access while at the Website, and the internet address of the Website, if any, from which you linked directly to the Website. This information is not personally identifiable.

We may obtain this information by placing a "cookie" on your computer's hard drive so we can recognize you as a return user and personalize your experience. A cookie is a piece of data that enables us to track and target your preferences. The cookie will be stored on your computer's hard drive until you remove it. We may also use temporary or "session" cookies to help you shop. These cookies will expire when you place an order. As with most internet browsers you can erase this information from your computer's hard drive, block all cookies or even receive a warning before a cookie is placed on your system. Click on your Browsers Help button for more information. If you reject our cookies, you may still use the website, but you may be limited in the use of some of the features. Some of our business partners may also use cookies on the website. However, we have no access to, or control over, these cookies and do not accept any responsibility for such use.

Shiseido Cosmetics uses non-personally identifiable information for internal business and marketing purposes and to help it administer and improve this website. Shiseido Cosmetics may also use this information to provide information about this website to its affiliates, advertisers, partners, potential business partners and other unaffiliated entities.

**B. Personally Identifiable Information**

Personally Identifiable Information is any information that concerns you individually and would permit someone to contact you, for example, your name, address, telephone/fax number, social security number, email address or any information you submitted to this Website that identifies you individually.

Personally identifiable information may be collected by Shiseido Cosmetics if you choose to communicate with Shiseido Cosmetics through email, via this Website, by telephone, in writing, by placing an order, by completing a user registration form or online survey, or by such other means.

Shiseido Cosmetics will not collect any personally identifiable information about you unless you provide it. Therefore, if you do not want Shiseido Cosmetics to obtain any personally identifiable information about you, please do not provide to Shiseido Cosmetics any such information. You can visit and browse our websites without revealing personally identifiable information about yourself.

When you submit your personally identifiable information on the website, you are giving your consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

**C. Use of Personally Identifiable Information**

Shiseido Cosmetics may use the personally identifiable information collected through our websites primarily for such purposes as: helping to establish and verify the identity of users; opening, maintaining, administering and servicing users' accounts or memberships; processing, servicing or enforcing transactions and sending related communications; providing services and support to users; improving the website, including tailoring it to users' preferences; providing users with product or service updates, promotional notices and offers, and other information about Shiseido Cosmetics and its affiliates; responding to your questions inquiries, comments and instructions; maintaining the security and integrity of its systems.

**D. Non-Disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information**

Shiseido Cosmetics does not provide personally identifiable information to unaffiliated third parties for their use in marketing directly to you without your consent.

**E. Disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information**

Shiseido Cosmetics may use unaffiliated companies to help it maintain and operate its websites, process and fulfill orders or for other reasons related to the operation of its business, and those companies may receive your personally identifiable information for that purpose. Shiseido Cosmetics may also disclose personally identifiable information about you in connection with legal requirements, such as in response to an authorized subpoena, governmental request or investigation, or as otherwise permitted by law. Further, as Shiseido Cosmetics' business develops, it may sell or buy corporate assets, and in such transactions customer information will be shared with such third parties and may be one of the transferred business assets.

**F. Children Under 13**

This website is directed toward and designed for use by persons aged 13 or older. Shiseido Cosmetics will not approve applications of, or establish or maintain accounts or memberships for, any child whom Shiseido Cosmetics knows to be under the age of 13. Shiseido Cosmetics does not solicit or knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If Shiseido Cosmetics nevertheless discovers that it has received personally identifiable information from an individual who indicates that he or she is, or whom Shiseido Cosmetics otherwise has reason to believe is, under the age of 13, Shiseido Cosmetics will delete such information from its systems. Additionally, a child's parent or legal guardian may request that the child's information be corrected or deleted from Shiseido Cosmetics’ files by contacting us at [customerservice@shiseidousa.com](mailto:customerservice@shiseidousa.com).  

**G. Links**

This Website may contain links to or from other websites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites. This Privacy Policy applies only to the information we collect on this Website. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of other websites you link to from this Website or otherwise visit.

**H. Security**

We implement various security measures in accordance with industry standards to protect the security of your personal information both online and offline. If you have any questions about security at the Website, you can contact us at the customer service link on this Website. Examples of certain security measures that we take include:

  * We use industry-standard Secure Sockets Layer ("SSL") authentication for online transactions made on our site. SSL authentication and encryption of the information that you send to us over the Internet helps protect your online transaction information from third party interception.  
  * Your credit card information is never used except to issue refunds and charges for orders placed on our Website. 
  * We will only reveal the last four digits of your credit card for verification purposes. We never display your full credit card number once it has been entered. 
  * We do not store, un-encrypted, your credit card number after processing your payment

However, despite all of our efforts, there is always a risk that third parties may unlawfully intercept transmissions of personal information. This reality is true of all Internet use. As a result, we cannot ensure the security of any information you transmit, and you transmit all information at your own risk.

**I. Notification of Changes**

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post the revised policy here. As we may make changes at any time without notifying you, we suggest that you periodically consult this Privacy Policy. Please note that our rights to use your personally identifiable information will be based on the privacy policy in effect at the time the information is used.

**J. Changes to Your Personal Information**

You have the ability to review, change and/or correct the personally identifiable information you provide us by contacting us at the customer service link on this Website.  If you are a registered user, you can also review, change or correct your personal information at any time by clicking here. You may request that we deactivate your account by contacting us at the customer service link on this Website.

**K. Unsubscribe**

From time to time, Shiseido Cosmetics and its affiliates may wish to send you message updates about Shiseido Cosmetics, its websites, its affiliates, promotions, security or the administration of our websites or other updates. If you would prefer not to receive future email communications from Shiseido Cosmetics and its affiliates, an unsubscribe link is provided on every communication you receive from Shiseido Cosmetics, or you may contact us at the customer service link on this Website.
